ANNOUNCER: October is inventory time.
So right now, Statler Toyota is making
the best deals of the year...
...on all 1985-model Toyotas.
You won't find a better car...
...at a better price with better service
anywhere in Hill Valley.
NEWSCASTER: The Senate is expected
to vote on this today.
In other news, officials at
the Pacific Nuclear research facility...
...have denied the rumor
that a case of missing plutonium...
...was in fact stolen
from their vault two weeks ago.
A Libyan terrorist group had claimed
responsibility for the alleged theft.
However, officials now attribute
the discrepancy to a simple clerical error.
The FBI, which is investigating the matter,
had no comment.
[Buzzer blares]
MARTY: Doc?
Doc?
Hello! Anybody home?
Einstein, come here, boy.
[Marty whistles]
MARTY: What's going on? God.
Jesus!
That is disgusting.
[Marty muttering]
[Clocks ticking]
[Machine humming]
[Humming grows louder]
[Humming grows very loud]
[Dial clicking]
[Electric guitar note plays]
[Marty grunts]
[Marty groaning]
Rock 'n' roll.
[Alarm bell ringing]
MARTY: Yo.
DOC: Marty, is that you?
Doc. Where are you?
DOC: Thank God I've found you. Meet me
at Twin Pines Mall tonight at 1:15.
I made a breakthrough.
I'll need your assistance.
1:15 in the morning?
Doc, what's going on?
MARTY: Where you been all week?
DOC: Working.
MARTY: Is Einstein with you?
DOC: Yeah, he's right here.
You left your equipment on all week.
DOC: My equipment. That reminds me, Marty.
Do not hook up to the amplifier.
There's a slight possibility of overload.
Yeah. I'll keep that in mind.
DOC: Good. I'll see you tonight. Don't forget.
DOC: 1:15 a.m., Twin Pines Mall.
MARTY: Right.
[Clocks all ringing, chiming, cuckooing]
DOC: Are those my clocks I hear?
MARTY: Yeah, it's 8:00.
DOC: Perfect! My experiment worked!
They're all exactly 25 minutes slow!
Wait a minute, Doc.
Are you telling me that it's 8:25?
DOC: Precisely.
MARTY: Damn!
I'm late for school.
[The Power of Love playing]
MARTY: Jennifer.
JENNIFER: Strickland's looking for you.
If you get caught,
it'll be four tardies in a row.
All right, come on. I think we're safe.
This time it wasn't my fault.
The doc set all his clocks 25 minutes slow.
The doc?
Am I to understand you're still hanging
around with Dr. Emmett Brown, McFly?
Tardy slip for you, Miss Parker.
And one for you, McFly.
I believe that's four in a row.
Let me give you a nickel's worth
of free advice, young man.
This so-called Dr. Brown is dangerous.
He's a real nutcase.
Hang around with him,
you'll end up in big trouble.
Yes, sir.
You got a real attitude problem.
You're a slacker.
You remind me of your father
when he went here. He was a slacker, too.
Can I go now, Mr. Strickland?
Your band is on the roster for
the dance auditions after school today.
Why even bother?
You don't have a chance.
You're too much like your old man.
No McFly ever amounted to anything
in the history of Hill Valley.
Yeah, well, history is going to change.
Next, please.
[Synthesizer playing]
All right.
We're the Pinheads.
MARTY: One, two, three.
[Playing Power of Love]
Okay, that's enough. Thank you, fellas.
Hold it, fellas.
I'm afraid you're just too darn loud.
Next, please.
Next group, please.
ANNOUNCER: Re-elect Mayor Goldie Wilson.
Progress is his middle name.
MARTY: "Too loud." I can't believe it.
We'll never get a chance
to play in front of anybody.
Marty, one rejection
isn't the end of the world.
I just don't think I'm cut out for music.
But you're really good,
and your audition tape is great.
You've got to send it in
to the record company.
-It's like Doc's always saying.
-I know.
If you put your mind to it,
you can accomplish anything.
That's good advice.
All right. What if I send in the tape
and they don't like it?
What if they say I'm no good?
What if they say, "You got no future"?
I can't take that kind of rejection.
I'm starting to sound like my old man.
-He's not that bad.
-Save the clock tower.
He's letting you borrow the car
tomorrow night.
Check out that 4x4.
MARTY: That is hot.
ATTENDANT: Back her up.
Someday, Jennifer. Someday.
Wouldn't it be great
to take that truck up to the lake?
Throw a couple of sleeping bags
in the back.
Lie out underneath the stars.
-Stop it.
-What?
Does your mom know?
About tomorrow night?
No, get out of town. My mom thinks
I'm going camping with the guys.
My mother would freak out
if she knew I was going with you.
I'd get the standard lecture about...
...how she never did that stuff
when she was a kid.
Look, I think the woman was born a nun.
She's just trying to keep you respectable.
She's not doing a very good job.
Terrible.
WOMAN: Save the clock tower.
Save the clock tower.
Mayor Wilson is sponsoring
an initiative to replace that clock.
Thirty years ago, lightning struck that
clock tower and the clock hasn't run since.
We at the Hill Valley Preservation Society
think it should be preserved the way it is...
...as part of our history and heritage.
MARTY: There's a quarter.
WOMAN: Thanks.
WOMAN: Don't forget to take a flyer.
Save the clock tower!
Where were we?
[Car horn honks]
JENNIFER: Right about here.
MAN: Jennifer!
It's my dad. I've got to go.
MARTY: I'll call you tonight.
I'll be at my grandma's.
Here, let me give you the number.
'Bye.
[Power of Love music playing]
[Dog barking]
RADIO DISPATCHER:
Bravo, Tango, Delta 6-2-9.
Tow for impoundment.
Any unit, please respond.
MARTY: Perfect. Just perfect.
[Biff speaking muffled]
BIFF: I can't believe you'd loan me your car...
...without telling me it had a blind spot.
I could've been killed.
Now, Biff, I never noticed...
...that the car had any blind spot before
when I would drive it.
Hi, son.
BIFF: Are you blind, McFly?
How else do you explain
that wreck out there?
MR. MCFLY: Biff, can I assume...
...that your insurance
is going to pay for the damage?
My insurance? It's your car.
Your insurance should pay.
Who's going to pay for this?
I spilled beer when the car smashed
into me. Who'll pay my cleaning bill?
And where's my reports?
I haven't finished those up yet,
but I figured since they weren't due 'til...
Hello? Hello? Anybody home?
Think, McFly. Think!
I got to have time to get them retyped.
Do you realize what would happen
if I hand in my reports in your handwriting?
I'll get fired.
You wouldn't want that to happen,
would you?
-Would you?
-Of course not.
I wouldn't want that to happen.
Now, look.
I'll finish those reports tonight...
...and I'll run them on over
first thing tomorrow.
Not too early. I sleep in Saturday.
Your shoe's untied.
Don't be so gullible, McFly.
Got the place fixed up nice.
I have your car towed to your house...
...and all you got for me is lite beer?
What are you looking at, butthead?
Say hi to your mom for me.
I know what you're going to say, son...
...and you're right.
You're right.
But...
Biff just happens to be my supervisor...
...and I'm afraid I'm just not
very good at confrontations.
But the car, Dad.
[Car driving away]
MARTY: I mean, he wrecked it.
He totaled it.
I needed that car tomorrow night, Dad.
Do you have any idea
how important this was to me?
MR. MCFLY: I know, and all I can say is, I'm...
I'm sorry.
MR. MCFLY: Believe me, Marty, you're better off...
...without having to worry
about all the aggravation...
...and headaches of playing at that dance.
DAVID: He's absolutely right.
The last thing you need is headaches.
[Mr. McFly laughing]
[David laughing]
[TV audience applauding]
Kids, we're going to have to
eat this cake by ourselves.
Your Uncle Joey didn't make parole again.
[Mrs. McFly sighs]
It would be nice
if you all dropped him a line.
MARTY: Uncle "Jailbird" Joey?
He's your brother, Mom.
Yeah. It's a major embarrassment,
having an uncle in prison.
We all make mistakes in life, children.
DAVID: Goddamn it. I'm late.
MRS. MCFLY: David, watch your mouth!
You come here and kiss your mother
before you go.
Come on, Mom.
Make it fast. I'll miss my bus.
DAVID: See you later, Pop.
[David exclaims]
Time to change that oil.
[Laughing]
LINDA: Marty.
I'm not your answering service.
While you were outside
pouting over the car...
...Jennifer Parker called you twice.
MRS. MCFLY: I don't like her.
Any girl who calls up a boy
is just asking for trouble.
LINDA: Mom. There's nothing wrong
with calling a boy.
I think it's terrible. Girls chasing boys.
When I was your age,
I never chased a boy or called a boy or...
...sat in a parked car with a boy.
LINDA: Then how am I ever
supposed to meet anybody?
Well, it'll just happen.
Like the way I met your father.
That was so stupid.
Grandpa hit him with the car.
It was meant to be.
[Linda sighs]
Anyway...
...if Grandpa hadn't hit him,
then none of you would have been born.
Yeah, well.
I don't understand what Dad was doing
in the middle of the street.
MRS. MCFLY:
What was it, George? Bird-watching?
What, Lorraine? What?
Anyway, your Grandpa
hit him with the car...
...and brought him into the house.
He seemed so helpless.
Like a little lost puppy,
and my heart just went out to him.
LINDA: Yeah, we know.
You've told us this story a million times.
You felt sorry for him.
You decided to go with him
to the Fish Under the Sea dance.
No. It was
the Enchantment Under the Sea dance.
Our first date. I'll never forget it.
It was the night of that terrible
thunderstorm, remember, George?
[Indistinct chatter on TV]
Your father kissed me
for the first time on that dance floor.
It was then that I realized...
...that I was going to spend
the rest of my life with him.
[Mr. McFly laughing]
Oh, no.
[Music playing on radio]
[Telephone ringing]
[Sighing]
Hello.
DOC: Marty, you didn't fall asleep, did you?
MARTY: Doc.
No. No, don't be silly.
DOC: Listen, this is very important.
I forgot my video camera.
Can you pick it up at my place
on your way to the mall?
Yeah. I'm on my way.
Einstein! Where's the doc, boy?
[Einstein whining]
[Machine humming]
[Gate unlocking]
[Mysterious instrumental music]
[Engine revving]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Steam rushing]
Doc!
-Marty! You made it!
-Yeah.
Welcome to my latest experiment. This is
the one I've been waiting for all my life.
Well, it's a DeLorean...
All your questions will be answered.
Roll tape and we'll proceed.
-Is that a Devo suit?
-Never mind that now.
DOC: Not now.
MARTY: I'm ready.
Good evening. I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
I'm in the Twin Pines Mall parking lot.
It's Saturday morning,
October 26, 1985, 1:18 a.m.
This is temporal experiment number one.
DOC: Come on, Einie. Get in there.
In you go. Sit down.
Put your seat belt on.
[Einstein grunting]
MARTY: Okay.
Please note that Einstein's clock...
...is in precise synchronization
with my control watch.
DOC: Got it?
MARTY: Right. Check, Doc.
DOC: Have a good trip, Einstein.
Watch your head.
MARTY:
You got that thing hooked up to the car?
DOC: Watch this.
MARTY: Yeah. Okay.
MARTY: Got it.
Jesus!
Not me! The car!
[Tires squealing]
[Engine revving]
If my calculations are correct...
...when this baby hits 88 miles per hour...
...you're going to see some serious shit.
[Remote control beeping]
[Tires squealing]
Watch this!
[Beeping growing faster]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Doc laughs]
What did I tell you?
88 miles per hour!
The temporal displacement occurred
exactly 1:20 a.m. and zero seconds!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ, Doc!
You disintegrated Einstein!
Calm down. I didn't disintegrate anything.
The molecular structure of both Einstein
and the car are completely intact.
Then where the hell are they?
The appropriate question is,
"When the hell are they?"
Einstein has just become
the world's first time traveler.
DOC: I sent him into the future.
One minute into the future, to be exact.
At precisely 1:21 a.m. and zero seconds...
...we shall catch up with him
and the time machine.
[Dramatic instrumental music ends]
Wait a minute, Doc.
Are you telling me that
you built a time machine...
...out of a DeLorean?
-The way I see it...
...if you're going to build a time machine
into a car, why not do it with style?
Besides, the stainless-steel construction
made the flux dispersal...
[Watch beeping]
Look out!
[Tires squealing]
[Remote control beeps]
[Time machine steaming and creaking]
[Doc gasps]
MARTY: What? Is it hot?
DOC: It's cold. Damn cold.
[Doc laughing]
Einstein, you little devil!
Einstein's clock is exactly one minute
behind mine and still ticking!
MARTY: He's okay.
DOC: He's fine.
He's completely unaware
that anything happened.
As far as he's concerned,
the trip was instantaneous.
That's why his watch is exactly
one minute behind mine.
He skipped over that minute to
instantly arrive at this moment in time.
I'll show you how it works.
First, you turn the time circuits on.
[Machine powering up]
[Machine whirs]
DOC: This tells you where you're going,
this where you are and this where you were.
Input your destination time on this keypad.
Say you want to see the signing
of the Declaration of Independence.
[Machine bleeps]
DOC: Or witness the birth of Christ.
Here's a red-Ietter date
in the history of science.
November 5, 1955.
Yes, of course.
What happened?
That was the day I invented time travel.
I remember it vividly.
I was standing on my toilet
hanging a clock.
The porcelain was wet.
I slipped, hit my head on the sink.
When I came to, I had a revelation.
A vision. A picture in my head.
A picture of this.
This is what makes time travel possible.
The flux capacitor.
Flux capacitor?
It's taken almost 30 years and my family
fortune to realize the vision of that day.
My God, has it been that long?
Things have certainly changed around here.
I remember when this was all farmland
as far as the eye could see.
Old man Peabody owned all of this.
He had this crazy idea
about breeding pine trees.
This is...
This is heavy-duty, Doc. This is great.
Does it run on regular unleaded gasoline?
Unfortunately, no. It requires something
with a little more kick. Plutonium.
Plutonium. Wait a minute.
Are you telling me
that this sucker is nuclear?
Keep rolling there.
No, this sucker's electrical...
...but I need a nuclear reaction to generate
the 1.21 gigawatts of electricity I need.
You don't just walk into a store
and buy plutonium.
Did you rip that off?
Of course. From a group of Libyans.
They wanted me to build them a bomb.
I took the plutonium and gave them a
bomb casing full of pinball machine parts.
DOC: Come on. Let's get you a radiation suit.
MARTY: Jesus!
[Breathing distorted by suit]
[Sucking]
It's safe now. Everything's lead-Iined.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
DOC: Don't lose those tapes now.
I need that as a record.
Let's put this back here. There we go.
Almost forgot my luggage.
Who knows if they got
cotton underwear in the future.
-I'm allergic to all synthetics.
-The future.
-That's where you're going.
-Right.
25 years. I've always dreamed of seeing
the future, looking beyond my years...
...seeing the progress of mankind.
MARTY: Why not?
I'll also be able to see
who wins the next 25 World Series.
MARTY: Doc.
Look me up when you get there.
Indeed I will. Roll 'em.
[Doc clearing throat]
I, Dr. Emmett Brown...
...am about to embark
on an historic journey.
What am I thinking of?
I almost forgot to bring extra plutonium.
How do I expect to get back?
One pellet, one trip.
I must be out of my mind.
[Einstein barking]
What is it?
[Ominous instrumental music]
My God.
They found me.
I don't know how, but they found me.
DOC: Run for it, Marty!
MARTY: Who?
Who do you think? The Libyans!
[Man shouting in Arabic]
Holy shit!
[Gunshots firing]
I'll draw their fire!
Doc, wait!
[Doc screaming]
No!
Bastards!
[Shouting in Arabic]
[Grunting]
[Gun clicking]
[Swearing in Arabic]
[Grunting]
Go!
[Engine stalling]
[Tires squealing]
[Engine starting]
[Machine beeping]
[Gunshots firing and ricocheting]
[Shouting]
Come on! Move! Goddamn it!
MARTY: Jesus!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Holy shit!
Let's see if you bastards can do 90.
[Tires squealing]
[Rumbling over ground]
[Screaming]
[Crashing]
[Chickens clucking]
[Crickets chirping]
[Dog barking distantly]
[Door creaks open]
[Car blinker clicking]
WOMAN: Pa, what is it?
What is it, Pa?
Looks like an airplane without wings.
That ain't no airplane. Look.
[Hydraulics hissing]
[Muffled breathing]
[Screaming]
Don't look!
MARTY: Listen...
[Cows mooing]
Hello.
Excuse me.
Sorry about your barn.
[Gunshot fires]
It's already mutated into human form!
Shoot it!
Take that, you mutated son of a bitch!
[Screaming]
BOY: Wait!
BOY: Shoot it, Pa!
MAN: My pine! Why you...
[Gunshot fires]
MAN: You space bastard! You killed my pine!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Tires squealing]
MARTY: Okay, McFly.
Get a grip on yourself. It's all a dream.
Just a very intense dream.
[Brakes squealing]
[Mysterious instrumental music]
[Somber instrumental music]
MARTY: Listen, you got to help me.
WOMAN: Don't stop, Wilbur!
It can't be.
[Machine beeps]
This is nuts.
[Engine stalling]
Come on.
Perfect.
[Machine beeping insistently]
[Mr. Sandman playing]
[Car honking]
[Bell dings]
[Gas attendants speaking]
[Mr. Sandman continuing]
[Boy counting]
[Bell chiming]
ANNOUNCER: Remember,
fellow citizens, the future is in your hands.
If you believe in progress,
re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
Progress is his middle name.
Mayor Red Thomas' progress platform...
...means more jobs, better education...
...bigger civic improvements
and lower taxes.
On election day,
cast your vote for a proven leader.
Re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
MARTY: This has got to be a dream.
[Davy Crockett playing on jukebox]
MAN: Hey, kid. You jump ship?
-What?
-What's with the life preserver?
I want to use the phone.
It's in the back.
MARTY: Brown.
Great. You're alive.
[Watch beeping]
[Marty sighs]
[Phone ringing]
Come on.
MARTY: Do you know where 1640 Riverside...
MAN: Are you going to order, kid?
Yeah.
Give me a Tab.
I can't give you a tab
unless you order something.
Right. Give me a Pepsi Free.
MAN: You want a Pepsi, pal,
you're going to pay for it.
Just give me something
without any sugar in it, okay?
Something without sugar.
[Door opens]
BIFF: McFly.
What are you doing?
Biff.
I'm talking to you, McFly, you Irish bug!
GEORGE: Biff. Guys. How are you doing?
BIFF: You got my homework finished?
Actually, I figured
since it wasn't due 'til Monday...
Hello? Hello? Anybody home?
Think, McFly. Think!
I got to have time to recopy it.
You realize what would happen if I hand in
my homework in your handwriting?
I'll get kicked out of school.
You wouldn't want that to happen,
would you?
-Would you?
-Of course not.
-No.
-I wouldn't want that to happen.
-What are you looking at, butthead?
-Get a load of his life preserver.
Dork thinks he's going to drown.
BIFF: How about my homework, McFly?
Okay, Biff.
I'll finish that up tonight and then I'll
bring it over first thing tomorrow morning.
Not too early. I sleep in Sundays.
Your shoe's untied!
Don't be so gullible, McFly.
-I don't want to see you in here again.
-Okay. All right. Bye-bye.
-What?
-You're George McFly!
Yeah. Who are you?
Why do you let those boys
push you around like that for?
They're bigger than me.
Stand tall. Have some respect for yourself.
If you let people walk over you now,
they'll walk over you the rest of your life.
Look at me. You think
I'll spend my life in this slop house?
MAN: Watch it, Goldie.
GOLDIE: No, sir!
GOLDIE: I'll do something.
I'll go to night school.
One day, I'm going to be somebody.
That's right. He's going to be mayor.
Yeah, I'm...
Mayor!
Now that's a good idea!
I could run for mayor.
-A colored mayor. That'll be the day.
-Wait and see. I will be mayor.
I'll be the most powerful man
in Hill Valley...
...and I'm going to clean up this town.
Good. You can start by sweeping the floor.
Mayor Goldie Wilson.
I like the sound of that.
[Bicycle bell rings]
Hey, Dad! George! Hey, you on the bike!
He's a peeping Tom!
Dad!
[Horn honking]
[Dogs barking]
Wait a minute. Who are you?
Stella! Another one of these damn kids
jumped in front of my car!
Come out here!
Help me take him in the house!
[Thunder rumbling]
Mom?
That you?
LORRAINE: There, there, now.
Just relax.
You've been asleep
for almost nine hours now.
I had a horrible nightmare.
I dreamed that I went back in time.
It was terrible.
LORRAINE: Well...
...you're safe and sound now
back in good old 1955.
1955?
[Marty gasping]
You're my...
My name is Lorraine.
LORRAINE: Lorraine Baines?
MARTY: Yeah.
But you're...
You're so...
You're so thin!
Just relax, Calvin.
You got a big bruise on your head.
[Panting]
[Marty exclaiming]
Where are my pants?
Over there...
...on my hope chest.
I've never seen
purple underwear before, Calvin.
Calvin?
Why do you keep calling me Calvin?
That is your name, isn't it? Calvin Klein.
It's written all over your underwear.
I guess they call you Cal, huh?
No, actually, people...
...call me Marty.
[Sighing]
Pleased to meet you, Calvin...
Marty...
...Klein.
-Do you mind if I sit here?
-No. Fine.
No. Good. Fine. Good.
That's a big bruise you have there.
[Marty shouts]
STELLA: Lorraine, are you up there?
Oh, my God! It's my mother!
LORRAINE:
Quick! Put your pants back on!
STELLA:
Marty, how long have you been in port?
MARTY: Excuse me?
STELLA: I guessed you're a sailor.
That's why you wear that life preserver.
Coast guard.
Sam, here's the young man you hit
with your car. He's all right. Thank God.
What were you doing
in the middle of the street?
Don't pay attention to him.
He's in one of his moods.
Quit fiddling with that thing.
Come in here to dinner.
STELLA: You already know Lorraine.
This is Milton, this is Sally...
...that's Toby, and over there
in the playpen is little baby Joey.
MARTY: So, you're my uncle Joey.
Better get used to these bars, kid.
STELLA:
Yes. Joey just loves being in his playpen.
He cries whenever we take him out,
so we leave him in there all the time.
Well, Marty, I hope you like meat loaf.
-Well, listen, I really ought to...
-Sit here, Marty.
Sam, stop fiddling with that thing
and come in here and eat your dinner.
[Sam chortling]
Look at it roll.
Now we can watch
Jackie Gleason while we eat.
[Muffled voices on TV]
Our first television set.
Dad just picked it up today.
Do you have a television?
Well, yeah.
You know, we have two of them.
Wow! You must be rich.
Honey, he's teasing you.
Nobody has two television sets.
[Marty exclaiming]
I've seen this one. This is a classic.
This is where Ralph dresses up
as a man from space.
What do you mean, you've seen this?
It's brand-new.
Yeah, well, I saw it on a rerun.
What's a rerun?
You'll find out.
You know, Marty,
you look so familiar to me.
Do I know your mother?
Yeah, I think maybe you do.
STELLA: Then I'll call her.
I don't want her to worry about you.
You can't.
[Stuttering]
That is, nobody's home.
Yet.
Listen.
Do you know where Riverside Drive is?
It's on the other end of town.
A block past Maple. East end of town.
A block past Maple.
That's John F. Kennedy Drive.
Who the hell is John F. Kennedy?
LORRAINE: Mother?
With Marty's parents out of town...
...don't you think
he ought to spend the night?
After all,
Dad almost killed him with the car.
That's true, Marty.
I think you should spend the night.
I think you're our responsibility.
-Well, gee, I don't know.
-He can sleep in my room.
MARTY: I got to go!
Thanks very much. You were all great.
See you all later.
Much later.
[Door closes]
He's a very strange young man.
He's an idiot.
Comes from upbringing.
His parents are probably idiots, too.
Lorraine, you ever have a kid
who acts that way, I'll disown you.
[Knocking on door]
[Electronic warbling]
MARTY: Doc?
Don't say a word.
DOC: No names. I want
to know nothing about you.
MARTY: Listen, Doc...
DOC: Quiet!
DOC: Don't tell me anything.
MARTY: You got to help...
DOC: Quiet.
[Electronic warbling]
I'm going to read your thoughts.
Let's see now.
You come here from a great distance?
-Yeah. Exactly.
-Don't tell me!
DOC: You want me to subscribe
to the Saturday Evening Post.
-No.
-Not a word now!
Quiet.
Donations.
You want me to make a donation...
...to the Coast Guard Youth Auxiliary.
Doc...
[Electronics grow silent]
...I'm from the future.
I came here in a time machine
that you invented.
Now, I need your help
to get back to the year 1985.
My God!
Do you know what this means?
It means that
this damn thing doesn't work at all!
MARTY: You got to help me. You are the only
one who knows how your time machine works.
[Whispering] Time machine?
I haven't invented any time machine.
Okay. I'll prove it to you.
Look at my driver's license. Expires 1987.
Look at my birthday.
I haven't even been born yet.
And look at this picture.
It's my brother, my sister and me.
Look at her sweatshirt, Doc.
"Class of 1984"?
DOC: Pretty mediocre photographic fakery.
They cut off your brother's hair.
I'm telling the truth.
You got to believe me.
Then tell me, future boy...
...who's president of the United States
in 1985?
-Ronald Reagan.
-Ronald Reagan? The actor?
[Doc exclaims]
Then who's vice president? Jerry Lewis?
DOC: I suppose Jane Wyman is the First Lady.
MARTY: Wait, Doc!
DOC: And Jack Benny is treasury secretary.
MARTY: Listen to me.
I've had enough jokes for one evening.
Good night, future boy!
MARTY: No, wait, Doc.
MARTY: The bruise on your head.
I know how that happened. You told me.
You were standing on your toilet
hanging a clock...
...and you fell
and hit your head on the sink.
That's when you got the idea
for the flux capacitor which...
...is what makes time travel possible.
[Mysterious instrumental music]
MARTY: There's something wrong with
the starter, so I hid it here.
DOC: After I fell off my toilet...
...I drew this.
MARTY: The flux capacitor.
[Electric crackling]
It works!
[Doc laughing]
I finally invent something that works!
You bet your ass it works.
We've got to sneak this back
to my laboratory.
We've got to get you home!
This is it.
DOC ON TV:
Never mind that now.
DOC: Why, that's me! Look at me!
-I'm an old man!
-I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
I'm in the Twin Pines Mall parking lot.
Thank God, I've still got my hair.
What's this thing I'm wearing?
This is a radiation suit.
Radiation suit?
Of course. 'Cause of all the fallout
from the atomic wars.
This is truly amazing.
A portable television studio.
No wonder your president has to be
an actor. He has to look good on TV.
MARTY: This is the part coming up.
This sucker's electrical but I need a nuclear
reaction to generate the 1.21 gigawatts...
What did I just say?
...this sucker's electrical,
but I need a nuclear reaction...
-...to generate the 1.21 gigawatts of...
-1.21 gigawatts!
1.21 gigawatts.
DOC: Great Scott!
What the hell is a gigawatt?
How could I have been so careless?
1.21 gigawatts!
Tom, how am I going to generate
that kind of power?
It can't be done, can it?
MARTY: Doc, look.
All we need is a little plutonium.
DOC: I'm sure that in 1985 plutonium is
available in every corner drugstore...
...but in 1955, it's a little hard to come by.
Marty, I'm sorry,
but I'm afraid you're stuck here.
Doc, stuck here? I can't be stuck here.
I got a life in 1985.
-I got a girl.
-Is she pretty?
Doc, she's beautiful.
She's crazy about me. Look at this.
Look what she wrote here.
That says it all.
Doc, you're my only hope.
Marty, I'm sorry, but the only power source
capable of generating...
...1.21 gigawatts of electricity
is a bolt of lightning.
MARTY: What did you say?
DOC: A bolt of lightning.
Unfortunately, you never know
when or where it's ever going to strike.
We do now.
This is it!
This is the answer.
It says here that a bolt of lightning...
...is going to strike the clock tower
at 10:04 p.m. next Saturday night!
If we could somehow harness
this lightning...
...channel it into the flux capacitor...
...it just might work.
Next Saturday night
we're sending you back to the future!
All right. Saturday's good.
I can spend a week in 1955.
I can hang out. You can show me around.
That is out of the question.
You must not leave this house.
You must not see or talk to anybody.
Anything you do can have repercussions
on future events. Do you understand?
Yeah. Sure. Okay.
Marty...
...have you interacted with anybody else
today besides me?
Yeah, well, I might've sort of
bumped into my parents.
Great Scott! Let me see that photograph
again of your brother.
Just as I thought. This proves my theory.
Look at your brother.
MARTY:
His head's gone. It's like it's been erased.
Erased from existence.
They really cleaned this place up.
Looks brand-new.
DOC: According to my theory, you interfered
with your parents' first meeting.
If they don't meet, they won't fall in love,
get married or have kids.
That's why your brother's disappearing.
Your sister will follow, and unless
you repair the damage, you're next.
MARTY: Sounds heavy.
DOC: Weight has nothing to do with it.
Which one's your pop?
[Bell ringing]
That's him.
Okay. Okay, you guys.
[George pretending to laugh]
Very funny.
You guys are being real mature.
Maybe you were adopted.
GEORGE: Okay, real mature, guys.
GEORGE: Okay, pick up my books.
STRICKLAND: McFly.
That's Strickland.
Jesus, didn't that guy ever have hair?
Shape up, man. You're a slacker.
Do you want to be a slacker
for the rest of your life?
No.
-What did your mother see in him?
-I don't know.
I guess she felt sorry for him
'cause her dad hit him with the car.
He hit me with the car.
That's the Florence Nightingale effect.
It happens in hospitals when
nurses fall in love with their patients.
Go to it, kid.
George, buddy.
I have been looking all over for you.
You remember me,
the guy who saved your life the other day?
-Yeah.
-There's somebody I'd like you to meet.
Lorraine?
Calvin!
I'd like you to meet
my good friend George McFly.
Hi. It's really a pleasure to meet you.
-How's your head?
-Good. Fine.
I've been worried about you
ever since you ran off the other night.
Are you okay?
[Bell ringing]
-I'm sorry. I have to go.
-Come on!
Isn't he a dreamboat?
-She didn't even look at him.
-This is more serious than I thought.
Your mother is infatuated with you
instead of your father.
Wait a minute, Doc.
Are you trying to tell me
that my mother has got the hots for me?
-Precisely.
-This is heavy.
There's that word again. "Heavy."
Why are things so heavy in the future?
Is there a problem with the Earth's gravity?
The only way we're going to
get them to mate is if they're alone.
You've got to get them to interact...
...in some sort of social...
-You mean like a date?
-Right!
What kind of date?
What do kids do in the '50s?
They're your parents.
You must know them.
What are their common interests?
What do they like to do together?
Nothing.
DOC: Look! There's a rhythmic
ceremonial ritual coming up.
The Enchantment Under the Sea dance!
They're supposed to go to this.
-That's where they kiss for the first time.
-All right, kid.
You stick to your father like glue
and make sure he takes her to that dance.
MARTY: George, buddy...
...remember that girl
I introduced you to, Lorraine?
What are you writing?
Stories.
MR. MCFLY: Science fiction stories
about visitors...
...coming down to Earth
from other planets.
Get out of town!
I didn't know you did anything creative.
-Let me read some.
-No, no.
I never let anybody read my stories.
MARTY: Why not?
What if they didn't like them?
What if they told me I was no good?
I guess that would be pretty hard
for somebody to understand.
No. No, not hard at all.
So anyway, George. About Lorraine.
She really likes you.
She told me to tell you
that she wants you to ask her...
...to the Enchantment
Under the Sea dance.
-Really?
-Yeah.
All you got to do is go over there
and ask her.
Right here, right now, in the cafeteria?
What if she said no? I don't know
if I could take that kind of rejection.
Besides, I think she'd rather go
with somebody else.
MARTY: Who?
Biff.
-Don't kid around. Come on.
-Come on. Leave.
BIFF: You know you want it.
You know you want me to give it to you.
Shut your filthy mouth.
I'm not that kind of girl.
Maybe you are
and you just don't know it yet.
Get your meat hooks off of me.
MARTY: You heard her.
She said, get your meat hooks...
...off.
MARTY: Please.
What's it to you, butthead?
BIFF: You been looking for a fight.
[People exclaiming]
Since you're new here,
I'm going to cut you a break...
...today.
So why don't you make like a tree...
...and get out of here.
[Boy laughing]
MARTY: George!
GEORGE: Why do you keep following me?
George, I'm telling you,
if you do not ask Lorraine to that dance...
...I'll regret it for the rest of my life.
-I can't go.
I'll miss my favorite TV program,
Science Fiction Theatre.
Yeah, but Lorraine wants to go with you.
Give her a break.
I'm just not ready
to ask Lorraine out to the dance...
...and not you
or anybody else on this planet...
...is going to make me change my mind.
MARTY: Science Fiction Theatre.
[Muffled breathing]
[Loud rock music plays]
[Stops music]
Who are you?
[Plays music]
[Stops music]
MARTY: [Muffled] Silence, Earthling.
My name is Darth Vader.
I am an extraterrestrial
from the planet Vulcan.
Marty!
[Car honks]
-Marty! Marty!
-George, buddy.
You weren't at school.
What have you been doing?
I overslept. I need your help.
I have to ask Lorraine out,
but I don't know how to do it.
Keep your pants on. She's over in the cafe.
God! How do you...?
MARTY: What made you change your mind?
Last night, Darth Vader came down
from planet Vulcan...
...and told me that if I didn't
take Lorraine out, he'd melt my brain.
Let's just keep this brain-melting stuff
to ourselves, okay?
-Yeah. Yeah.
-All right. There she is.
Just go in there and invite her.
GEORGE: But I don't know what to say.
MARTY: Say anything.
Say whatever's natural,
the first thing that comes into your mind.
Nothing's coming to my mind.
Jesus. It's a wonder I was even born.
-What? What?
-Nothing.
Tell her destiny brought you together.
Tell her she is the most beautiful girl
you have ever seen in the world.
Girls like that stuff.
-What are you doing?
-I'm writing this down. This is good stuff.
-Yeah. Okay. Can you take care of that?
-Right.
[The Wallflower playing]
[People chattering]
Lou, give me a milk.
Chocolate.
GEORGE: Lorraine.
My density...
...has popped me to you.
What?
[Mumbling]
What I meant to say was...
Wait a minute.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
GEORGE: Yes.
Yes. I'm George. George McFly.
I'm your density.
I mean...
...your destiny.
[Sighing]
BIFF: McFly.
[Music stops]
I thought I told you never to come in here.
Well, it's going to cost you.
How much money you got on you?
GEORGE: How much do you want, Biff?
[Biff grunts]
[All gasping]
BIFF: All right, punk.
-Now I'm going to...
-Biff. What's that?
[Biff grunts]
[All gasping]
That's Calvin Klein. My God, he's a dream.
Kid! Kid, stop! Stop!
[Boy protesting]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
MARTY: I'll get it back to you.
BOY: You broke it!
Come back here!
[Cars honking]
Look at him go!
Get him!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
BIFF: To the car! Go!
GIRL: What's that thing he's on?
BOY: A board with wheels.
He's an absolute dream.
THUG 1: Come on, come on!
THUG 2: Look out for the car!
[Shouting]
[Tires squealing]
[Screaming]
[Brakes squealing]
[Woman grunts]
[Tires squealing]
BIFF: I'm going to ram him.
ALL: Shit!
[Brakes squealing]
[Crowd murmuring]
[Exclaiming]
Thanks a lot, kid.
I'm going to get that son of a bitch.
-Where does he come from?
-Yeah, where does he live?
I don't know...
...but I'm going to find out.
[Audio rewinding]
DOC ON TV: My God.
They found me.
I don't know how, but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
[Audio rewinding]
My God.
They found me.
I don't know how, but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
Doc?
Hi, Marty. I didn't hear you come in.
Fascinating device, this video unit.
Listen, Doc.
MARTY: I haven't told you about ...
DOC: One shouldn't know about his own destiny.
-You don't understand.
-I do.
If I know too much
I endanger my own existence...
...just as you've endangered yours.
You're right.
Let me show you my plan
for sending you home.
Please excuse the crudity of this model.
I didn't have time to build it to scale
or paint it.
-It's good.
-Thank you.
We run industrial-strength electrical cable
from the top of the clock tower...
...down, suspending it over the street
between these two lampposts.
Meanwhile, we've outfitted the time
vehicle with this big pole and hook...
...which runs directly
into the flux capacitor.
At the calculated moment...
...you start off from down the street...
...driving directly toward the cable,
accelerating to 88 miles per hour.
According to the flyer, at precisely
10:04 p.m. this Saturday night...
...lightning will strike the clock tower,
electrifying the cable...
...as the connecting hook makes contact...
...thereby sending 1.21 gigawatts
into the flux capacitor...
...and sending you back to 1985.
DOC: All right, now. Watch this.
You wind up the car and release it.
I'll simulate the lightning.
[Wind-up mechanism twisting]
[Electrical humming]
Ready.
Set.
Release.
[Car whirring]
[Marty exclaims]
[Gasps]
MARTY: You're instilling me
with a lot of confidence.
Don't worry. I'll take care of ideas.
You take care of your pop.
By the way...
...what happened today? Did he ask her out?
-I think so.
-What did she say?
[Knocking at door]
It's your mom! She's tracked you down!
Quick! Let's cover the time machine.
Hi, Cal... Marty.
MARTY: Lorraine.
How did you know I was here?
I followed you.
This is my doc... My uncle...
...Doc Brown.
-Hi.
LORRAINE:
Marty, this may seem a little forward...
...but I was kind of wondering...
...if you'd ask me to the...
...Enchantment Under the Sea dance
on Saturday?
You mean...
You mean nobody's asked you?
LORRAINE: No.
Not yet.
-What about George?
-George McFly?
He's kind of cute and all, but not...
Well...
I think a man should be strong...
...so he can stand up for himself...
...and protect the woman he loves.
Don't you?
Yeah.
I still don't understand.
How am I supposed to
go to the dance with her...
...if she's already going
to the dance with you?
Well, because, George,
she wants to go with you.
She just doesn't know it yet.
That's why we got to show her
that you, George, are a fighter.
You're somebody who stands up
for yourself and will protect her.
Yeah, but I've never picked a fight
in my entire life.
Look, you're not going
to be picking a fight, Dad...
Dad-dad-daddy-o.
You're coming to her rescue, right?
Let's go over the plan again.
8:55, where are you going to be?
I'm going to be at the dance.
-And where am I going to be?
-You'll be in the car, with her.
Right around 9:00,
she's going to get very angry with me.
Why is she going to get angry with you?
Well, because, George, nice girls get angry
when guys take advantage of them.
[George exclaims]
-You're going to go touch her on her...
-No. No, George, look.
It's just an act, right?
So, 9:00, you're strolling
through the parking lot.
You see us struggling in the car.
You walk up, you open the door,
and you say...
Your line, George.
[Exclaiming]
Hey, you, get your damn hands off her!
-You really think I ought to swear?
-Definitely.
Goddamn it, George, swear.
Okay. So now you come up.
You punch me in the stomach.
I'm out for the count, right?
And you and Lorraine
live happily ever after.
You make it sound so easy.
I just... I wish I wasn't so scared.
There's nothing to be scared of.
All it takes is self-confidence.
You know, if you put your mind to it...
...you can accomplish anything.
ANNOUNCER:
Hill Valley weather this Saturday night.
Mostly clear, with some scattered clouds.
Lows tonight, in the upper forties.
Are you sure about this storm?
Since when can weathermen predict
the weather, let alone the future?
You know, Marty,
I'm going to be very sad to see you go.
You've made a difference in my life,
given me something to shoot for.
Just knowing
that I'm going to be around to see 1985.
That I'm going to succeed in this!
That I'm going to have a chance
to travel through time!
[Emotional instrumental music]
It's going to be hard
waiting 30 years to talk to you...
...about everything that's happened
in the past few days.
I'm really going to miss you, Marty.
I'm going to miss you.
-Doc, about the future...
-No!
We've agreed that information about
the future can be extremely dangerous.
Even if your intentions are good,
it can backfire drastically.
Whatever you've got to tell me I'll find out
through the natural course of time.
"Dear Dr. Brown:
"On the night that I go back in time...
"...you will be...
"...shot by terrorists.
"Please take whatever precautions are
necessary to prevent this terrible disaster.
"Your friend...
"...Marty."
'Evening, Dr. Brown. What's with the wire?
Just a little weather experiment.
-What you got under here?
-No! Don't touch that!
Some new, specialized
weather-sensing equipment.
Got a permit for that?
Of course I do.
DOC: Just a second.
Let me see if I can find it here.
[Playing rock 'n' roll music]
[Music continues faintly]
[Marty sighs]
Do you mind if we...
...park for a while?
That's a great idea. I'd love to park.
I'm almost 18 years old.
It's not like I've never parked before.
What?
Marty, you seem so nervous.
Is something wrong?
No.
[Opening bottle]
Lorraine, what are you doing?
I swiped it from
the old lady's liquor cabinet.
Yeah, well, you shouldn't drink.
-Why not?
-Because you...
You might regret it later in life.
Marty, don't be such a square.
Everybody who's anybody drinks.
Jeez, you smoke too?
You're beginning to sound
just like my mother.
[Jazz song ending]
[Crowd applauding]
We're going to take a little break,
but we'll be back in a while...
...so don't nobody go nowhere.
Marty? Why are you so nervous?
Lorraine...
...have you ever...
...been in a situation where you knew
you had to act a certain way, but when...
...you got there, you didn't know
if you could go through with it?
You mean like how
you're supposed to act on a first date?
Sort of.
I think I know exactly what you mean.
You do?
You know what I do in those situations?
-What?
-I don't worry.
[Marty protesting muffled]
LORRAINE: This is all wrong.
I don't know what it is...
...but when I kiss you, it's like I'm kissing...
...my brother.
I guess that doesn't make any sense,
does it?
Believe me...
...it makes perfect sense.
[Footsteps approaching]
Somebody's coming.
[Marty grunts]
You caused $300 damage to my car,
you son of a bitch...
...and I'm going to take it out of your ass.
Hold him.
Let him go, Biff. You're drunk.
Well, lookee what we have here.
No! Stay right here with me.
Come on, Lorraine.
LORRAINE: Let me go!
MARTY: Leave her alone!
Take him in back. I'll be right there.
Just admit that you want it. Come on.
Well, go on. This ain't no peep show.
[Marty grunts]
[Lorraine and Biff struggling]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
THUG 1: Hey, let's put him in there.
THUG 2: Yeah!
That's for messing up my hair.
What the hell are you doing to my car?
Hey, beat it, spook.
This don't concern you.
Who you calling spook, peckerwood?
THUG 2: Listen, guys...
...I don't want to mess
with no reefer addicts, okay?
MARVIN: Get home to your mama, boy.
THUG 1: Biff!
THUG 2: Hurry, Biff!
MARTY: [Muffled] Let me out of here!
[Pounding and shouting]
Reginald, where are your keys?
MARTY: [Muffled] The keys are in the trunk.
MARVIN: Say that again?
MARTY: I said, the keys are in here.
LORRAINE: [Muffled] Let me go!
BIFF: [Muffled] Come on!
Hey you, get your damn hands off...
[Sighing]
I think you got the wrong car, McFly.
George, help me! Please!
Just turn around, McFly, and walk away.
LORRAINE: Please, George.
BIFF: Are you deaf?
BIFF: Close the door and beat it.
[Lorraine whimpering]
No, Biff. You leave her alone.
All right, McFly.
You're asking for it...
...and now you're going to get it.
[George groaning]
Stop it!
Biff, you'll break his arm!
[Gasping]
LORRAINE: Biff, no!
MARVIN: Give me a hand here, Reginald.
[Exclaiming]
Damn it, man! I sliced my hand!
-Whose are these?
-Mine.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
You're going to break his arm!
Biff! Biff, leave him alone!
Let him go! Let him go!
[Biff laughing]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Biff grunts]
[George panting]
Are you okay?
[Tender instrumental music]
Who is that guy?
That's George McFly.
That's George McFly?
Excuse me.
[Thunder rumbling]
The storm.
Guys, you got to get back in there
and finish the dance.
Look at Marvin's hand.
He can't play with this hand,
and we can't play without him.
Marvin, you got to play.
They kiss for the first time at the dance.
If there's no music, they can't dance.
If they can't dance and kiss,
then they can't fall in love and I'm history.
The dance is over unless you know
somebody that can play the guitar.
[Playing Earth Angel]
This is for all you lovers out there.
MARVIN: [Singing]
"Earth Angel, Earth Angel
"Will you be mine
"My darling dear"
LORRAINE:
George, aren't you going to kiss me?
I don't know.
Scram, McFly. I'm cutting in.
[Lorraine protesting]
[Playing dissonant notes]
"Earth Angel, Earth Angel
"The one I adore"
Hey, boy, you all right?
I can't play.
George!
[Boy laughing]
[Oppressive instrumental music]
[Ominous instrumental music]
[Boy laughing]
George!
George.
Excuse me.
[Boy grunts]
[Uplifting instrumental music]
MARVIN: [Singing]
"The vision of your happiness
"Earth Angel, Earth Angel
"Please be mine
"My darling dear
"Love you for all time
"I'm just a fool
"A fool in love
"with you"
[Crowd applauding]
MARVIN: Yeah, man, that was good.
Let's do another one.
No. I got to go.
Come on, man.
Let's do something that really cooks.
Something that cooks.
[Cheering]
MARTY: All right.
MARVIN: All right!
All right.
All right, this is an oldie, but...
Well, it's an oldie where I come from.
All right, listen, this is a blues riff in B.
Watch me for the changes,
and try and keep up, okay?
[Playing Johnny B. Goode]
"Way down in Louisiana
Down in New Orleans
"Way back up in the woods
among the evergreens
"There stood a log cabin
made of earth and wood
"Where lived a country boy
name of Johnny B. Goode
"He never ever learned
to read or write so well
"He could play the guitar
just like he's ringin' a bell
"Go go
Go Johnny go, go
"Go Johnny, go, go, go
"Go Johnny go, go"
George, I heard you laid out Biff.
Nice going.
You ever think of
running for class president?
MARTY: [Singing] "Johnny B. Goode
"Go Johnny go, go
"Go Johnny go, go, go
"Johnny B. Goode"
Chuck! Chuck, it's Marvin.
Your cousin, Marvin Berry?
You know that new sound
you're looking for?
Well, listen to this.
[Music growing wilder]
[Marty playing heavy metal riffs]
[Feedback]
[Playing sustained high-pitch note]
[Amplifiers humming]
I guess you guys aren't ready for that yet...
...but your kids are going to love it.
[Jazz playing faintly]
Lorraine.
Marty, that was very interesting music.
Yeah.
I hope you don't mind, but George
asked if he could take me home.
Great! Good. Good, Lorraine.
I had a feeling about you two.
I have a feeling, too.
Listen, I got to go, but...
...I wanted to tell you that
it's been educational.
LORRAINE: Marty, will we ever see you again?
I guarantee it.
Well, Marty, I want to thank you
for all your good advice.
I'll never forget it.
Right, George.
Well, good luck, you guys.
[Marty exclaims]
One other thing.
If you guys ever have kids...
...and one of them,
when he's eight years old...
...accidentally sets fire
to the living room rug...
...go easy on him.
Okay.
Marty. Such a nice name.
Damn! Where is that kid?
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Damn!
Damn! Damn!
[Brakes squealing]
DOC: You're late!
Do you have no concept of time?
Hey, come on. I had to change.
Do you think I'm going back
in that zoot suit?
The old man really came through.
It worked.
He laid out Biff in one punch.
I didn't know he had it in him.
He's never stood up to Biff in his life.
-Never?
-No. Why? What's the matter?
All right!
Let's set your destination time.
[Machine beeping]
DOC: This is the exact time you left.
Let's send you back at exactly
the same time.
It'll be like you never left.
Now, I painted a white line
on the street way over there.
That's where you'll start from.
I've calculated the precise distance...
...taking into account
the acceleration speed...
...and wind resistance retroactive
from the moment the lightning strikes...
...which will be in exactly
7 minutes and 22 seconds.
When this alarm goes off, you hit the gas.
Right.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Well, I guess that's everything.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
DOC: See you in about 30 years.
I hope so.
Don't worry!
As long as you hit that wire...
...with the connecting hook
at precisely 88 miles an hour...
...the instant the lightning
strikes the tower...
DOC: ...everything will be fine.
MARTY: Right.
[Thunder rumbling]
-What's the meaning of this?
-You'll find out in 30 years.
It's about the future, isn't it?
DOC: Information about the future.
MARTY: Wait a minute.
I warned you about this, kid.
The consequences could be disastrous!
Doc, that's a risk
you're going to have to take.
-Your life depends on it!
-No!
I refuse to accept the responsibility.
In that case, I'll tell you straight out.
[Thunder crashing]
Great Scott!
[Thunder clapping]
You get the cable,
I'll throw the rope down to you.
MARTY: Right! I got it!
[Wind howling]
[Gasping]
Doc!
DOC: Come on, come on. Let's go!
MARTY: All right! Take it up!
Go!
Doc!
[Shouting indistinctly]
I have to tell you about the future.
DOC: What?
MARTY: I have to tell you about the future!
What?
On the night I go back in time you get...
[Clock bells ringing]
Doc!
[Doc screaming]
Go!
-No, Doc!
-Look at the time!
You've got less than four minutes.
Please, hurry!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Bell ringing]
DOC: Yeah!
Damn it, Doc!
Why did you have to tear up that letter?
If I only had more time.
Wait a minute. I got all the time I want.
I got a time machine.
I can just go back early and warn him.
Okay. Ten minutes ought to do it.
Okay. Time circuit's on.
Flux capacitor, fluxing.
Engine running. All right.
[Engine stops suddenly]
No. No, no.
Come on. Come on. Not this time.
[Doc screaming]
[Engine clicking]
[Grunts]
MARTY: Come on.
[Alarm ringing]
Here we go. Here we go.
This time. Come on.
Please. Please. Come on!
[Shouts]
[Engine starts]
[Tires squealing]
[Grunts]
[Screaming]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Doc.
[Wind blowing]
[Doc shouting gleefully]
[Helicopter whirring]
[Music playing on radio]
[Explosive crashing]
[Tires squealing]
Crazy drunk driver.
[Marty exclaims]
All right. Fred.
You look great. Everything looks great.
[Marty panting]
1:24.
I still got time. I'm coming, Doc!
[Engine dies]
No! No, not again!
Come on! Come on!
[Tires squealing]
[Terrorists shouting indistinctly]
Libyans.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
MARTY: No!
Bastards!
TERRORIST: Go!
[Tires squealing]
[Gunshots firing]
MARTY: Doc! Doc!
[Marty sobbing]
[Tender instrumental music]
MARTY: No!
You're alive.
Bulletproof vest?
How did you know?
I never got a chance to tell you.
What about all that talk
about screwing up future events?
The space-time continuum?
Well, I figured, what the hell.
[Uplifting instrumental music]
MARTY: So how far ahead are you going?
About 30 years. It's a nice round number.
Look me up when you get there, all right?
Guess I'll be about 47.
I will.
MARTY: Take care.
You, too.
Right. Bye-bye, Einie.
MARTY: And watch that re-entry.
It's a little bumpy.
You bet.
[Explosive crashing]
[Dog barking]
[Radio plays Back In Time]
What a nightmare.
LINDA: If Paul calls, tell him I'm working
at the boutique late.
DAVID:
Linda, I'm not your answering service...
...and somebody named Greg or Craig
called you just a little while ago.
LINDA: Which one was it?
DAVID: I can't keep up with your boyfriends.
[Marty calls]
MARTY: What the hell is this?
Breakfast.
DAVID: Did you sleep in your clothes again?
Yeah. I...
What are you wearing, Dave?
Marty...
...I always wear a suit to the office.
DAVID: You all right?
MARTY: Yeah.
MRS. MCFLY: We need a rematch.
MR. MCFLY: A rematch?
-Why? Were you cheating?
-No.
-Hello.
-Good morning.
Mom! Dad!
MR. MCFLY: Hit your head?
MRS. MCFLY: Are you okay?
You guys look great.
Mom, you look so thin.
Why, thank you, Marty. George!
Good morning, sleepyhead.
MRS. MCFLY: Good morning, kids.
DAVID AND LINDA: 'Morning.
LINDA: Marty, I almost forgot.
Jennifer Parker called.
I sure like her. She is such a sweet girl.
Isn't tonight the night of the big date?
What? What, Ma?
Aren't you going up to the lake?
You've been planning it for two weeks.
We talked about this.
How can I go to the lake?
The car's wrecked.
MR. MCFLY: Wrecked?
DAVID: Wrecked?
When did this happen? Why wasn't I told?
MR. MCFLY: I'm sure the car is fine.
DAVID: Why am I the last to know?
MR. MCFLY: See? There's Biff out there
waxing it now.
Now, Biff, I want to make sure we get
two coats of wax, not just one.
-I'm just finishing up the second coat now.
-Now, Biff, don't con me.
I'm sorry, Mr. McFly.
I meant I was just starting
on the second coat.
Biff. What a character.
Always trying to get away with something.
I've had to stay on top of Biff
ever since high school.
MR. MCFLY: But, if it wasn't for him...
MRS. MCFLY: We'd never have fallen in love.
Mr. McFly! Mr. McFly, this just arrived.
Hi, Marty. I think it's your new book.
Honey! Your first novel.
MR. MCFLY: I've always told you, if you put your
mind to it, you can accomplish anything.
Marty, here's your keys.
You're all waxed up, ready for tonight.
Keys?
[Tender instrumental music]
-How about a ride, mister?
-Jennifer!
Are you a sight for sore eyes.
MARTY: Let me look at you.
Marty, you're acting like
you haven't seen me in a week.
I haven't.
You okay?
Is everything all right?
MARTY: Yeah.
Everything is great.
[Explosive crashing]
[Brakes screeching]
Marty!
You've got to come back with me!
-Where?
-Back to the future.
What are you doing, Doc?
I need fuel.
Go ahead. Quick! Get in the car.
No, no. I just got here. Jennifer's here.
We're taking the new truck for a spin.
DOC: Bring her along. This concerns her, too.
What are you talking about?
What happens to us in the future?
-Do we become assholes or something?
-No, Marty.
Both you and Jennifer turn out fine.
It's your kids, Marty.
Something has got to be done
about your kids.
We better back up.
We don't have enough road to get up to 88.
Roads? Where we're going,
we don't need roads.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today